Dreams algorithm brings the algorithm is a minimum spanning tree algorithm that takes a graph as input
and file the subset of the edges of that graph, which form a tree that includes every vertex and has
the minimum sum of weights among all the trees that can be formed from that crop.
So the Prem's algorithm falls under a class of algorithms called greedy algorithms that find the local
optimum in the hopes of finding a global optimum.
We start from one vertex and keep adding edges with the lowest weight until we reach our goal.
The steps for implementing Prem's algorithms are as follows We start by analysing the minimum spanning
tree with a vertex chosen at random.
Find all edges that connect that connect the tree to new vertices and find the minimum and add it to
the tree.
The third step is keep repeating step number two until we get the minimum spanning tree, so that's
took an example.
Start with a weighted graph, I want from you to write this example down on your copy book in order
to understand it and in order to implement it with sea language and Java language and the next videos.
So in order to understand what we are going to do later on encoding, please understand this algorithm,
this animation.
So the first step we start with a weighted the graph here.
This is the way the graph and we choose the any in any starting point.
We start from C.
Choose a vertex, which is the vertex.
We choose the short edge from this vertex and add it.
The third step is adding the nearest vertex, not yet in the solution.
So we are getting the shortest way from this starting point.
We add.
The step number five, the shortest way with with the next with the next points, so f is that as near
to E and we add it to the path.
So we choose the nearest edge, not yet in the solution.
If there are multiple choices, so choose one at random.
If we have multiple choices, so he has a three and weighted city so we can choose either F or we can
choose either D..
So you can create.
In the previous step, even as see with Connected because it is having three waited three or you can
choose F, which is way that three you can choose at Atlanta, whatever you want.
So we have to choose E and F, and we choose C and D again, and now we implement until having the spanning
three Cell C will be connected with A.
This is the Prem's algorithm now.
Prince versus Cruz call algorithm guru skills algorithm is another popular minimum spanning tree algorithm
that uses a different logic to find that the unknown at three minimum spanning tree of a graph instead
of starting from a vertex scale algorithm, sort all the edges from the low way to high and keeps adding
keep adding the lowest edges, ignoring those edges that create a cycle.
So the premise algorithms complexity would be e loug v e represent the number of edges and log v the
v two percent that vertices no nets c that primes algorithm application.
We can see it in the laying laying cables of electrical wiring in network designed or to make protocols
in network cycles.
So this is the premise algorithm.
Now let's move to implement the coding of Prem's algorithm in C language and the next videos we are
going to implement.